Guide to the June D. Drake photographs
Oregon Historical Society Research Library
- Transportation, 1890-1950; Series 9; 170 photographic prints
  - Trains, 1890; circa 1910; 1912 (Box 15, Folder 21)
    All photographs taken prior to 1900 were originally taken by an unidentified photographer and reprinted by June D. Drake.
  - Trucks, circa 1920 (Box 15, Folder 22)
- Animals, 1920-1934; Series 10; 49 photographic prints
  - Bears, 1934 (Box 15, Folder 23)
  - Beavers--Dams, undated (Box 15, Folder 24)
  - Birds, undated (Box 15, Folder 25)
  - Deer--Deer hunting, undated (Box 15, Folder 26)
  - Dogs, 1926; undated (Box 15, Folder 27)
    Includes photographs of Bobbie the Wonder Dog, a Scotch Collie who found his way home to Silverton, Oregon, after being lost in Indiana in 1923.
  - Dogs (oversize material), undated (Box 17, Folder 23)
  - Ducks, undated (Box 15, Folder 28)
  - Elk, 1920 January 1 (Box 15, Folder 29)
  - Fish--Fish hatchery, circa 1925 (Box 15, Folder 30)
  - Fish--Rainbow trout, undated (Box 15, Folder 31)
  - Mice in trap, undated (Box 15, Folder 32)
  - Rabbits, undated (Box 15, Folder 33)
  - Snakes and snake charmer, undated (Box 15, Folder 34)
- June D. Drake historical collections, 1946; undated; Series 11; 44 photographic prints
  This series contains photographs that June D. Drake took of historical artifacts and other objects that he had obtained for his personal collection, which detailed the history of Silverton and its environs.
  - Art objects, undated (Box 15, Folder 35)
  - Confederate money, undated (Box 15, Folder 36)
  - Fossils found at Pinson Farm at Evan's valley, 1946 August 20 (Box 15, Folder 37)
  - Gun and powder horn, undated (Box 15, Folder 38)
  - Kazoo instruments, undated (Box 15, Folder 39)
  - Tools and engines, undated (Box 15, Folder 40)
- Copy work, 1881-1950; undated; Series 12; 165 photographic prints
  This series contains reproductions made by June D. Drake of photographs originally taken by other photographers, all unidentified. This copy work was commissioned by Drake's customers.
  - Reproductions of printed materials, 1881-1950 (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Reproductions of photomechanical prints, undated (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - Lumber industry--Transportation--Railroads, undated (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - Portraits--Children--Unidentified, circa 1900 (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - Portraits--Couples--Unidentified, undated (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - Portraits--Families--Disney family, undated (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - Portraits--Families--Pete Steffen family, 1918 (Box 16, Folder 7)
  - Portraits--Families--Unidentified, undated (Box 16, Folder 8)
  - Portraits--Groups--Unidentified, undated (Box 16, Folder 9)
  - Portraits--Groups--Unidentified (oversize material), undated (Box 19, Folder 16)
  - Portraits--Men--Identified, undated (Box 16, Folder 10)
  - Portraits--Men--Unidentified, undated (Box 16, Folder 11)
  - Portraits--Military, undated (Box 16, Folder 12)
  - Portraits--Pioneers, undated (Box 16, Folder 13)
    Copies of portraits made by June D. Drake for P. L. Brown.
  - Portraits--Women--Identified, undated (Box 16, Folder 14)
  - Portraits--Women--Unidentified, undated (Box 16, Folder 15)
  - Residences--Ireland--Cottage, undated (Box 16, Folder 16)
- Negatives, 1860-1955; Series 13; 20.34 cubic feet 56 document cases; 1 slim document case
  Series consists of Drake's original negatives, including glass lantern slides, glass negatives, and acetate negatives.
  Materials in this series are not available for direct access due to fragility. Researchers are asked to use digitized versions available online in OHS Digital Collections. Contact library staff for assistance.
  - Glass lantern slides and glass positives, 1860-1955 (Box 21)
  - Cirkut negatives, 1914-1920 (Box 22)
  - Cirkut negatives, 1921-1925 (Box 23)
  - Cirkut negatives, 1926-1930 (Box 24)
  - Cirkut negatives, 1930-1939 (Box 25)
  - Glass negatives, 5 x 7 inches, 1860-1955 (Box 26, Item 1-75)
  - Glass negatives, 5 x 7 inches, 1860-1955 (Box 27, Item 76-150)
  - Glass negatives, 5 x 7 inches, 1860-1955 (Box 28, Item 151-225)
  - Glass negatives, 5 x 7 inches, 1860-1955 (Box 29, Item 226-325)
  - Glass negatives, 5 x 7 inches, 1860-1955 (Box 30, Item 326-400)
  - Glass negatives, 5 x 7 inches, 1860-1955 (Box 31, Item 401-475)
  - Glass negatives, 5 x 7 inches, 1860-1955 (Box 32, Item 476-565)
  - Glass negatives, 5 x 7 inches, 1860-1955 (Box 33, Item 566-639)
  - Glass negatives, 5 x 7 inches, 1860-1955 (Box 34, Item 641-709)
  - Glass negatives, 5 x 7 inches, 1860-1955 (Box 35, Item 714-800)
  - Glass negatives, 5 x 7 inches, 1860-1955 (Box 36, Item 801-875)
  - Glass negatives, 5 x 7 inches, 1860-1955 (Box 37, Item 876-960)
  - Glass negatives, 5 x 7 inches, 1860-1955 (Box 38, Item 961-1035)
  - Glass negatives, 5 x 7 and 5 x 8 inches, 1860-1955 (Box 39, Item 1036-1135)
  - Glass negatives, 5 x 7 inches, 1860-1955 (Box 40, Item 1136-1210)
  - Glass negatives, 5 x 7 inches, 1860-1955 (Box 41, Item 1211-1285)
  - Glass negatives, 5 x 7 inches, 1860-1955 (Box 42, Item 1286-1360)
  - Glass negatives, 5 x 7 inches, 1860-1955 (Box 43, Item 1361-1435)
  - Glass negatives, 5 x 7 inches, 1860-1955 (Box 44, Item 1436-1510)
  - Glass negatives, 5 x 7 and 5 x 8 inches, 1860-1955 (Box 45, Item 1511-1600)
  - Glass negatives, 5 x 7 inches, 1860-1955 (Box 46, Item 1601-1675)
  - Glass negatives, 5 x 7 inches, 1860-1955 (Box 47, Item 1676-1750)
  - Glass negatives, 5 x 7 inches, 1860-1955 (Box 48, Item 1751-1825)
  - Glass negatives, 5 x 7 inches, 1860-1955 (Box 49, Item 1826-1900)
  - Glass negatives, 5 x 7 inches, 1860-1955 (Box 50, Item 1901-1985)
  - Glass negatives, 5 x 7 inches, 1860-1955 (Box 51, Item 1986-2060)
  - Glass negatives, 5 x 7 inches, 1860-1955 (Box 52, Item 2061-2140)
  - Glass negatives, 5 x 7 inches, 1860-1955 (Box 53, Item 2141-2215)
  - Glass negatives, 5 x 7 inches, 1860-1955 (Box 54, Item 2216-2272)
  - Glass negatives, 5 x 7 inches, 1860-1955 (Box 55, Item 2373-2356)
  - Glass negatives, 5 x 7 inches, 1860-1955 (Box 56, Item 2357-2443)
  - Glass negatives, 5 x 7 inches, 1860-1955 (Box 57, Item 2444-2528)
  - Glass negatives, 5 x 7 inches, 1860-1955 (Box 58, Item 2529-2612)
  - Glass negatives, 5 x 7 inches, 1860-1955 (Box 59, Item 2613-2700)
  - Glass negatives, 5 x 7 inches, 1860-1955 (Box 60, Item 2701-2788)
  - Glass negatives, 5 x 7 inches, 1860-1955 (Box 61, Item 2789-2875)
  - Glass negatives, 5 x 7 inches, 1860-1955 (Box 62, Item 2876-2957)
  - Glass negatives, 5 x 7 inches, 1860-1955 (Box 63, Item 2958-2975)
  - Acetate negatives, 5 x 7 inches, 1860-1955 (Box 64, Item 2976-3225)
  - Acetate negatives, 5 x 7 and 3.5 x 4 inches, 1860-1955 (Box 65, Item 3226-3427)
  - Glass negatives, 8 x 10 inches, 1860-1955 (Box 66, Item 3228-3477)
  - Glass negatives, 8 x 10 inches, 1860-1955 (Box 67, Item 3478-3522)
  - Glass negatives, 8 x 10 and 5 x 8 inches, 1860-1955 (Box 68, Item 3523-3561)
  - Glass negatives, 8 x 10 inches, 1860-1955 (Box 69, Item 3562-3592)
  - Glass negatives, 8 x 10 inches, 1860-1955 (Box 70, Item 3593-3627)
  - Glass and acetate negatives, 8 x 10 and 6.5 x 8.5 inches, 1860-1955 (Box 71, Item 3628-3667)
  - Glass negatives, 8 x 10 and 6.5 x 8.5 inches, 1860-1955 (Box 72, Item 3668-3700)
  - Glass negatives, 8 x 10 and 6.5 x 8.5 inches, 1860-1955 (Box 73, Item 3701-3736)
  - Glass negatives, 8 x 10 inches, 1860-1955 (Box 74, Item 3737-3769)
  - Glass negatives, 8 x 10 and 5 x 7 inches, 1860-1955 (Box 75, Item 3770-3788)
  - Glass negatives, unnumbered, 8 x 10 and 6.5 x 8.5 inches, 1860-1955 (Box 76)
  - Acetate negatives, deteriorating, 5 x 7 inches, 1860-1955 (Box 77)